<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Melissa Keizer - User Experience Designer, Photographer and Visual Story Teller</title>
    <description>Personal website of Melissa Keizer - a UI/UX designer, front-end developer and photographer from Bangor, Northern Ireland.
</description>
    <link>http://melissakeizer.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://melissakeizer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 17:21:31 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 17:21:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My DIBI Conf Experience</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently ventured to the beautiful city of Edinburgh to attend the international conference for designers and developers known as &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dibiconference.com/&quot;&gt;Design It; Build It&lt;/a&gt;, or DIBI for short. The theme of the two day conference this year was “Risk.” Our best work often happens when we take creative risks, but with risk comes potential problems and fear of failure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the speakers spoke about ways in which we can embrace these risks, consider bold ideas, overcome project challenges, and in &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bashakalakha&quot;&gt;Basak Haznedaroglu’s&lt;/a&gt; case, how we as designers can be good agents for change within an organisation. The central points in her talk, along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tobiasahlin&quot;&gt;Tobias Ahlin’s&lt;/a&gt; talk, have echoed in my mind since the conference a few week ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-be-a-good-agent-for-change&quot;&gt;How to be a Good Agent for Change&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really looking forward to hearing from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bashakalakha&quot;&gt;Basak&lt;/a&gt;, as she has worked as the design lead on many of my favourite apps, including Foursquare, Swarm and Wunderlist. Her talk also interested me a lot because of its relevance to my role as a User Experience Designer at TheAppBuilder. TheAppBuilder toolkit is used by innovators and change agents in large organisations who often face significant resistance to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/dibi-conf-lanyard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dibi Conf Lanyard&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a UX Designer, I persistently champion the needs of the user, so Basak’s advice on how to make bold decisions and overcome anxieties regarding potential conflict with other people involved with the product was very insightful. She talked about how we as designers shouldn’t settle for out of the box design guides like Google’s Material Design, but to design for our curiosity and create something unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/dibi-conf-basak.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dibi Conf&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Basak Haznedaroglu speaking about being an agent for change&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As she discussed this I immediately thought of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.swarmapp.com/&quot;&gt;Swarm’s&lt;/a&gt; delightful user experience, with its quirky user interface, friendly illustrated stickers to attach to check-ins and exciting animations when you achieve mayor status or add a new place to your log. Every detail matters, so it’s important to agonise over the seemingly “little things,” such as the language and interactions used in an app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/swarmapp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swarm App&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only did she speak on what we can do as individuals, but also on what we can do collectively as a company or as a design team to ensure we embrace change and take positive actions towards reaching our goals. As a company, we must build with intention and learn how to say “no” as a product that says yes to everything has no identity. We must respect user research to focus priorities and let features fight to be included in our product and prove their worth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;effective-innovation-with-design-bets&quot;&gt;Effective Innovation with Design Bets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another talk I found very valuable was that of &lt;a href=&quot;(https://twitter.com/tobiasahlin)&quot;&gt;Tobias Ahlin&lt;/a&gt;, a designer who has previously worked for Spotify and Github, who now works as the Lead Experience Designer at Minecraft in Sweden and teaches at creative business school Hyper Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tobias aims to democratize the creative process with the use of an innovation framework known as Design BETs (Belief Exploration Trees). The framework can be used to organise our ideas under one goal. Tobias used the example of a coffee shop whose goal is to increase their 30 day retention by 10 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/dibi-conf-tobias.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dibi Conf&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Tobias Ahlin speaking about design bets&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He began by creating a Belief Exploration Tree for the coffee shop listing 3 ways in which they could change with the intention to increase their retention rate – food, coffee &amp;amp; drinks and customer service. These can be branched out further, for example, they could make the customer service more personal, speedier or more unique. If they aimed to make the customer service more personal they could consider writing the customers’ names on the cups, similarly to Starbucks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the idea has been chosen we can flesh it out with a short description that describes the gist of it as well as a hypothesis describing what we expect to change (like increased customer delight and loyalty) which will lead to measurable impact, and what data or reasons lead us to believe this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole process was fascinating as it allows you to discern the most impactful areas and explore a wide range of ideas. The same framework can be applied to digital products like TheAppBuilder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/dibi-conf-friends.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dibi Conf&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Caroline Smith and I at DIBI Conf&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;two-inspiring-days&quot;&gt;Two Inspiring Days&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DIBI was packed with many more interesting talks, ranging from using behaviour models to ensure your app is the one to succeed in a crowded market, to how we should strive to create ethical products in an online world where you’re constantly being tracked without consent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event also gave me the opportunity to meet with like-minded friends old and new while staying in one of my favourite cities! After a super couple of days in Edinburgh I’ve returned to the office excited to work on improving &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theappbuilder.com&quot;&gt;TheAppBuilder&lt;/a&gt; and sharing what I learned with the team. Thanks for hosting such a great event, DIBI!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 00:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/dibiconf/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/dibiconf/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2016 Year in Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I always find it interesting to read the Year in Review posts of people I follow as it’s nice to get a glimpse into their life and find out what kind of goals they’re pursuing. This time I’ve decided to share my own  review of 2016, the personal highlights, a few things I’ve learned and what I can do better in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year I turned 25. I was expecting to have some sort of quarter-life crisis, but fortunately I soon came to the realisation that being a “proper adult” has its perks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;new-digs&quot;&gt;New Digs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, in September I moved out of my parent’s house, and into a lovely house with my boyfriend Mikey. It’s been so great. I love the little house we’re renting,  it’s so close to Bangor city centre and it’s only a few minutes away from Ward Park, making it perfect for morning runs and walks around the duck pond with my dog Matisse. It’s great to have more independence, create our own routine and get the chance to improve my culinary skills!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/our-new-home.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Our new home&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This year I moved into this lovely new house in Bangor with my boyfriend&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;half-marathon&quot;&gt;Half Marathon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of 2016, I made a resolution: I wanted to run a half marathon. I wasn’t a long-distance runner so I knew this goal was going to be challenging, but I needed to shake things up and test my tenacity! Fortunately my uncle Robert was up for the challenge too, providing me with accountability as well as a great running partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ensure we stayed committed, we signed up to Belfast City’s Half Marathon taking place on 18th September and decided to raise money for the Alzheimer’s Society, in memory of my grandmother, Jean Taylor, who we sadly lost to Alzheimer’s disease in December 2014. It definitely gave more meaning to our goal and kept us motivated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training was tough, but the rush of endorphins after each long run made it feel worth it. After months of training, race day was upon us. After 2 hours and 16 minutes of running, I crossed the finish line together with Robert. It felt so good!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the feelings of relief and achievement were intense after completing the half marathon. The icing on the cake was finding that we’d raised over £1000 for the Alzheimer’s Society!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/half-marathon-day.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;before the race&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Robert &amp;amp; I pictured before we ran the Belfast City Half Marathon&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;systems-not-goals&quot;&gt;Systems, not goals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Achieving the goal I’d set at the beginning of the year was a great boost. However I found that after running the half marathon, I lost the motivation to keep up my regular training schedule and my exercise regime was lacking for the couple of months before Christmas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading James Clear’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesclear.com/goals-systems&quot;&gt;post about systems vs goals&lt;/a&gt;, I realised that I need to commit to a system, for example, to a specific workout schedule rather than to just commit to a larger goal. This could have helped me to keep up regular training even afer the race was behind me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel&quot;&gt;Travel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the year I visited a few different countries and had some great holiday experiences. In May I visited Italy for the first time, sharing a few lovely days in Rome with my Mum. We explored the city, taking in the amazing architecture and tasting authentic italian cusine, it was the best! Check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://melissakeizer.exposure.co/roaming-rome&quot;&gt;photo story of the trip on Exposure&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/my-rome-trip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Rome trip&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My trip to Rome in May was one of the year&#39;s highlights&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With half of my family being dutch, I would visit Holland fairly regularly. However this summer, my family and I extended our trip and ventured to areas we’d never been before. We first spent a few days in Nunspeet visiting family, before making our way down to the picturesque village of Valkenburg in the south of Holland. We stayed in a gorgeous apartment that we found on AirBnb, overlooking a street filled with quaint little cafes and restaurants. It was the perfect place to unwind. On our journey back North we passed through Belgium so we could spend the day in the bustling city of Antwerp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/valkenburg.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;One from Valkenburg, Holland&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The picturesque village of Valkenburg that we visited as a family in the summer&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Mikey’s birthday, I’d arranged for us to spend a long weekend in Edinburgh, one of my favourite cities. During the last weekend in August we got to experience the Fringe Festival for the first time, journey through both the Old Town and New Town, and spend some good, quality time together. Of course we also attended Shane Todd’s (my favourite local comedian) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/KeizGoesBoom/status/769675438553755653&quot;&gt;very last stand-up gig&lt;/a&gt; of the festival and it didn’t fail to have me in stitches for an hour straight!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/greyfriars-bobby.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Visiting Greyfriars Bobby&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Visiting Greyfriars Bobby during our Edinburgh trip&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m definitely keen to do a bit more travelling in 2017. There’s so many places I’d love to visit and things I want to experience. I want to explore more scenic towns and cities, go on a hot air balloon, get closer to wildlife, scuba dive, sample the local dishes, and of course, take a lot more photos! Hopefully I’ll get the opportunity to tick a few of those things off by the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;side-hustle&quot;&gt;Side Hustle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the year I took on various freelance photography jobs, including a few pet photography sessions, which was awesome. While it’s always great to earn a little bit of extra income, another great benefit to taking on more jobs was the confidence building aspect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do photography mainly as a hobby, but I remember always feeling hugely nervous before any photography job, not completely trusting my own skills or creativity. However, as I got more gigs, I felt the nerves disappear and a sense of confidence grow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/maggie-the-puppy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;maggie the puppy&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;This year I got to photograph even more cute dogs. Oh and check out my new watermark!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal website got a refresh in 2016 too. I wanted the site to better represent my design tastes and make it feel a little more sophisticated, so I redesigned it and wrote new content, before rebuilding it and pushing it live in October. I also recruited my good friend and Eyekiller colleague, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/juleco&quot;&gt;Julie&lt;/a&gt;, to design new branding to represent my work. You can read a lot more about this in my blog post, “&lt;a href=&quot;http://melissakeizer.com/journal/rebranded-and-refreshed/&quot;&gt;rebranded and refreshed&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;market-myself-better&quot;&gt;Market Myself Better&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If there’s one area I aim to improve in 2017, it would be my social media presence. While I was happy to get a few paid pet photography sessions, I didn’t do much to market my services. I setup a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/melissakeizerphotography/&quot;&gt;Facebook Page&lt;/a&gt; and posted new photos every now and then, but I should have harnessed the power of Facebook ads and used Facebook competitions as a way to gain more likes and exposure or simply post updates and photos on a more regular basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the days begin to get brighter I’d like to take on more work, especially if it involves animals. My first port of call will be designing and printing new business cards and/or leaflets and keeping my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/melissakeizerphotography/&quot;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;work-and-career&quot;&gt;Work and Career&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eyekiller.com/&quot;&gt;Eyekiller&lt;/a&gt; in 2015 with the aim to improve my design skills and be immersed in a wide range of projects, knowing I’d be learning a lot by working with a very talented team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my first year, I was confident that I was becoming a better visual designer, but I was also really interested in learning about creating great user experiences. I was very happy to hear that Eyekiller were sending me on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://uxtraining.com/&quot;&gt;UX Foundation Training Course&lt;/a&gt; led by &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.linkedin.com/in/garethdunlop&quot;&gt;Gareth Dunlop&lt;/a&gt; back in May. It was a fun, insightful experience, consisting of lots of hands-on UX exercises and working in teams with great people from various industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/ux-course-complete.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;UX Course Complete&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Holding our certificates after successfully completing UX Foundation Training&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the year I’ve been able to utilise the UX research and testing methods I’d learned on several projects, including &lt;a href=&quot;https://themaclive.com/&quot;&gt;The MAC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fireflyfriends.com/uk/&quot;&gt;Firefly Friends&lt;/a&gt; and more recently, W5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-brand-new-challenge&quot;&gt;A Brand New Challenge&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a believer of being forever a student, so when an exciting opportunity came along that would push me out of my comfort zone and evolve my skills, I took it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can now happily announce that I’m joining the team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theappbuilder.com/&quot;&gt;TheAppBuilder&lt;/a&gt; in Belfast as their UX Designer. TheAppBuilder is a SaaS company that has built a platform that allows its users to create and manage mobiles apps. I’ll be focusing on developing the internal UX design process and improve the user experience and engagement with the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having worked at design agencies creating websites for various clients for the last few years, I’m excited to be working on a sole product. I’ll get the opportunity to dive deeper into user research, see how new app features or design changes fare in the hands of real users, and be forever iterating and improving the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I start at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theappbuilder.com/&quot;&gt;TheAppBuilder&lt;/a&gt; on Monday 16th January, wish me luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lets-go-2017&quot;&gt;Let’s Go, 2017&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To me, happiness is spending quality time with my favourite people, so I’ll be keeping that my top priority. I’m also hoping I can cross more fun experiences and personal achievements off my list this year, I’m feeling optimistic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to face fresh challenges in my new job, but it’ll be sad saying goodbye to the wonderful team at Eyekiller, who I’ve grown pretty fond of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d love to know how your year went and if you’ve set any resolutions for 2017, leave a note in the comments! 😊&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2017 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/2016-year-in-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/2016-year-in-review/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rebranded and refreshed</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of months ago I felt the overwhelming urge to update my personal website. I didn’t feel like the style of my site reflected me or my work anymore, plus I just wanted an excuse to experiment with some new ideas I had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to refresh my personal branding with something with a bit more personality that better represents me. I knew the right person to help me with this, fellow designer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://eyekiller.com&quot;&gt;Eyekiller&lt;/a&gt; and my desk neighbour, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/juleco&quot;&gt;Julie McClements&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-brand&quot;&gt;A new brand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Julie is always impressing me with her creative touch on everything she designs, from websites to wedding invites! We bounced a few ideas off each other and shared Pinterest boards before coming up with some nice ideas for the logo. She presented me with various concepts within days and after a little refining of our favourite concept, I had a finished logo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m really chuffed with the final outcome, Julie really hit the nail on the head for me. When thinking of a graphical element that I could use to represent me, I focused on my nationality. My father is dutch and my surname “Keizer” isn’t too common in this neck of the woods. A clog fits in perfectly with the dutch theme, so we ran with that idea for my brand. I also wanted something that represented me as a creative, as both a designer and a photographer, so the whimsical typeface she used was perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/melissa-keizer-branding-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My new branding&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The awesome branding created by my talented friend Julie McClements&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out more of Julie’s work on her &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/julecodesign/&quot;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-new-website&quot;&gt;A new website&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s funny how it seems to be much easier to settle on a design for a client website, but when it comes to your own, it’s a different story! I now have countless &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sketchapp.com/&quot;&gt;Sketch&lt;/a&gt; files with an array of designs that didn’t make the cut, though it was fun to play around with different layouts and styles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally arrived at a design that I was happy with. I love the use of large serif typefaces on websites and chose “FF Meta Serif” for my titles and for the main body text as it’s comfortable to read. I accompanied this with the sans-serif typeface “Montserrat” to tie in with my logo’s strapline. I kept the design fairly minimal, with a black, white and yellow colour palette and many of my photos used throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/my-website-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My new website&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A fresh look for my personal website&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the build, I used my favourite framework &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; as a basis for my site. It’s blog aware, uses files and folders instead of a database, uses markdown for blog posts and makes it easy to build and maintain various page templates with templating language Liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;keep-shipping&quot;&gt;Keep shipping&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My aim for the next couple of months is to populate the site with more rich content, in particular, case studies of some of the interesting web and UX projects I’ve worked on this year. For now, I just wanted to ship a site that felt a little more me.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 22:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/rebranded-and-refreshed/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/rebranded-and-refreshed/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I&#39;ll Photograph Your Pets!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you were to scan through my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/tinyspark_boom/&quot;&gt;Flickr portfolio&lt;/a&gt; it’s easy to see that I’m fond of taking photos of animals. I often visit zoos, animal sanctuaries, the local park or wherever else I can find four-legged critters to shoot. I thought, “wouldn’t it be nice if I had the chance to do this more, and on top of that, be paid to do it?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/cassie-by-melissa-keizer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo I took of Cassie the dog&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A lovely Spanish Water Dog I met and photographed named Cassie&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s my plan. I took on a range of freelance photography jobs last year, ranging from restaurant shoots and portrait sessions to fashion shows and an autumn wedding. However I’d love to be commissioned to take photos of animals, including cherished pets whose owners want lovely portraits of them to display in their home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;inspiration&quot;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dream of mine is already being lived by a few of my favourite photographers. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.charlottereeves.com.au/&quot;&gt;Charlotte Reeves&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://500px.com/dogbreathphotography&quot;&gt;Kaylee Greer&lt;/a&gt; are professional dog photographers who spend their days meeting adorable dogs and shooting their portraits, and their work is incredible!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/charlotte-reeves-fletcher.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Charlotte Reeves Photography&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I love the work of Brisbane photographer, Charlotte Reeves&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping I’ll be able to tap into the local market of owners who love their dogs, cats, horses or any of their other pets and want keepsakes in the form of gorgeous portraits they can hang on their wall, put in an album or post on Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;support-me-on-facebook&quot;&gt;Support me on Facebook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in an effort to market my services and share some of my work, I’ve created a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/melissakeizerphotography/&quot;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt; for my photography. You may notice that it’s populated with only my animal photography, as well as interesting links related to animals or photography. While I may share some of my other work from time to time, I’d like to keep it focused on animal photography and target the people who may be interested in having their pet’s portraits taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/melissakeizerphotography/&quot; class=&quot;image-link&quot;&gt;
   &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/melissakeizerphotography.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Support me on Facebook&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I recently set up a Facebook page, likes are appreciated!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping you can support me by liking or sharing my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/melissakeizerphotography/&quot;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;, so I can spread the word about my services and hopefully get some four-legged clients booked in soon. 😃&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2016 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/i-will-photograph-your-pet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/i-will-photograph-your-pet/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My New Sony A7ii</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve finally made the jump to full-frame photography as a few weeks ago I treated myself to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jessops.com/online.store/categories/products/sony/alpha-a7-mkii-compact-system-camera-body-95132/show.html&quot;&gt;Sony A7ii&lt;/a&gt; after lusting after it for months. Since I’ve had it for a few weeks now and used it for various photoshoots, I thought I’d share some of my thoughts on this camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before making the jump, I’d been using my Sony a580, a crop-sensor DSLR. In fact, the A7ii is now the 3rd Sony camera in my kit, which also includes my old (entry-level DSLR), the Sony a100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/sony-camera-lineup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Sony cameras&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My camera family - the Sony a100, the Sony a58- and the Sony a7ii&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-frame-mirrorless-compact-system-camera&quot;&gt;Full-frame Mirrorless Compact-System Camera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two main differences between my Sony A580 and my new Sony a7ii. One of which is that the A7ii is mirrorless compact-system camera, so works a little differently from a conventional DSLR. A traditional SLR camera will flip a mirror inside the body out of the way when it takes a photo, to let the light hit the sensor. However, the only barrier to light between the lens and the sensor on a mirrorless camera is the shutter curtain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that the camera uses an electronic viewfinder (instead of the traditional optical viewfinder) which allows you to check exposure as you’re taking the photo and avoids viewfinder black-out during shooting. Of course, this took a little getting used to, but being able to check my settings are ok while I shoot has been pretty useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other main difference is that the A7ii is full-frame, whereas my A580 was an APS-C crop sensor camera. Without going too much into what this means, the main difference is that a full-frame camera’s sensor has a wider field of view, over the “cropped” view a crop sensor has. This means a 35mm lens will show a lot more of the scene when on a full-frame camera, compared to a crop-sensor camera. There’s pros and cons for each, but I’ll go into that later!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-gear&quot;&gt;My Gear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with the camera, I bought the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jessops.com/online.store/categories/products/sony/55mm-f-1-8-za-lens-89675/show.html&quot;&gt;Sony 55mm f/1.8 lens&lt;/a&gt; from Jessops in Belfast. I love shooting with my 35mm prime lens on my A580, so I was after a lens with a focal length of around 50mm for my new full-frame camera, as this would give a similar field of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sony 55mm f/1.8 is pretty amazing and produces so super sharp images with awesome bokeh! It’s definitely a lens you’ll want to nab if you’re shooting with a camera from the Sony A7 range. A few weeks later I bought the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Sony-FE-28-F2-Lens/dp/B00UJRSO52/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1446407886&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=sony+28mm&quot;&gt;Sony 28mm f/2&lt;/a&gt; to give me the option of shooting a bit wider. For £360 it’s a bit of a bargain as it’s a great lens, though with many wide lenses, there is some distortion when shooting RAW, though it is fixable. I read an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stevehuffphoto.com/2015/04/06/the-sony-28mm-f2-fe-lens-review-by-steve-huff/&quot;&gt;interesting blog post&lt;/a&gt; about this lens that swayed me to buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s also worth noting that while the A7ii is more advantageous for the majority of shooting situations, my crop-sensor Sony a580 will still be my go-to camera for things like shooting animals at the zoo. This is because my Sigma 70-200mm telephoto lens will have longer reach on a crop sensor, so I can get closer to my subject. I’ve found it’s also been useful to have two good cameras on the go for busy shooting situations like a wedding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/my-sony-a7ii.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Sony a7ii&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My new Sony a7ii paired with the Sony 55mm f/1.8 lens&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-nitty-gritty&quot;&gt;The Nitty Gritty&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve had this camera for about 5 weeks now and used it in various shooting conditions, so I’ve been able to test it quite thoroughly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;low-light-and-high-iso&quot;&gt;Low Light and High ISO&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the primary reasons I wanted this full-frame camera was its good reputation for dealing with low-light scenes as I’m an avid natural light shooter and only use flash when necessary. I brought my new A7ii along to a dog show held inside a hall at Balmoral Park, where it was fairly dark and I still wanted some great photos of the lovely dogs I met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to use ISO 5000 quite comfortably, as there wasn’t much visible noise. However my images did start becoming quite grainy when I used IS0 6400. Since I avoid using ISOs higher than 1600 on my previous DSLR, this is pretty good going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/dalmation-dog-show.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A photo taken of a dalmation by my Sony A7ii&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Being able to happily shoot at ISO 5000 at the dog show - win &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also tested the auto-ISO feature, which allows you to set your aperture and shutter speed and it will choose a suitable ISO setting. While it works, it’s not afraid of choosing really high ISOs, higher than what I’d be comfortable with using, so I’d refrain from using this feature in low-lit scenes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;autofocus&quot;&gt;Autofocus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sony A7ii’s AF is fast and it’s sharp, and it didn’t let me down during a recent event I worked at. I was asked to cover the Autumn Fashion Show for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/mainstreetmystreet/?fref=ts&quot;&gt;Main Street My Street&lt;/a&gt; campaign, held inside Bob &amp;amp; Bert’s cafe in Bangor. I switched to AF-C (continuous focus) had no problem with keeping the models in focus as they walked toward me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/fashion-show-diptych.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Models at Fashion Show&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Shooting models walking the catwalk with continuous autofocus&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only real issue I’ve had with the autofocus on my A7ii is being able to pin-point the focus on the eyes of animals. I noticed this when taking photos of my little dog Matisse. I like using wide aperture to capture shots with low depth of field, but it this often means I miss the eyes as the focus is on the nose or eyebrow of my dog. While there is an “Eye AF” mode specially designed to focus on eyes, it seems to just work on humans. I can of course move the little focusing box around the screen to the eye, but I don’t always have time do this when shooting a hyper-active dog!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/matisse-castle-park.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Matisse&#39;s face&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The AF doesn’t always pinpoint Matisse’s eyes, but when it does, it’s sharp!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;manual-focus&quot;&gt;Manual Focus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On most occasions, I rely heavily on my camera’s AF, but in some circumstances you need to switch to manual. The A7iii has made manual focusing a lot easier with it’s “focus peaking” feature. When you turn this feature on and begin turning the focus wheel, you’ll see an area of the scene “sparkle” with a coloured glow showing up on the area in focus. This makes it a lot easier to get your manual focus spot on, see it in action &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BZFtPKgBM0U&quot;&gt;in this video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;custom-buttons&quot;&gt;Custom Buttons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a few more features the Sony A7ii has that really enhance its user experience. This includes the custom button settings on the camera that allow you to choose functions (out of an array of choices) for various buttons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commonly used functions and settings can be accessed quickly, like switching focus mode or area, setting monitor brightness and turning on SteadyShot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wifi-sharing&quot;&gt;Wifi Sharing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The camera has it’s own in-built wifi, so you can send images (including RAWs) straight to your phone using the Sony PlayMemories app. I like this feature as it lets me share a photo or two from a shoot before I’m home to upload them to my computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/my-sony-a7ii-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Sony a7ii&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I love the design of the Sony A7ii, it&#39;s pretty cute for a camera, right? &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tldr&quot;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To sum up, the Sony A7ii is a very impressive camera and after only a few weeks I feel like it will aid me in becoming a better, more confident photographer. I’ve listed a few of my personal pros and cons for purchasing this camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pros&quot;&gt;Pros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Full-frame quality in a cute little package, this camera is tiny compared to &lt;a href=&quot;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/loOC87Ni4x8/maxresdefault.jpg&quot;&gt;other full frame DSLRs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The autofocus is fast and reliable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The focus peaking feature makes manual focus a lot easier&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I love  its gorgeous design which pays homage to the vintage SLRS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pixels aren’t everything but it’s great having an extra 50% more (compared to my Sony a580)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The electronic viewfinder is great for ensuring your shot is exposed well as it allows you to preview the settings while composing the shot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Awesome low light ability and getting usable shots at high ISO ranges is great&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Using the custom buttons to quickly access your commonly used functions is handy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wifi in-built for sending photos to my iPhone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paired with Sony 55mm f/1.8 it’s amazing!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cons&quot;&gt;Cons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Photography is an expensive hobby but even more so when you start buying full-frame lenses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m starting from scratch again gear-wise as my current Sony Alpha gear is incompatible with the Sony A7ii&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s hard to pinpoint the autofocus on a small area (like my dog’s eyes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As with most mirrorless cameras, the battery life isn’t great. I had to buy two extra batteries. (The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00F8Q3S9Q?psc=1&amp;amp;redirect=true&amp;amp;ref_=oh_aui_detailpage_o09_s00&quot;&gt;Ex-Pro batteries&lt;/a&gt; are a good, cheaper alternative to the Sony branded ones)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There’s no battery cradle provided when you buy the camera (why so stingy Sony?!) so you have to charge batteries through the camera itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the benefits definitely outweigh the disadvantages, so if you’re thinking of upgrading your camera system, I’d highly recommend the Sony A7ii.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about picking up a Sony A7ii yourself, feel free to &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#104;&amp;#105;&amp;#064;&amp;#109;&amp;#101;&amp;#108;&amp;#105;&amp;#115;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#107;&amp;#101;&amp;#105;&amp;#122;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;email me&lt;/a&gt; or leave a comment if you have any questions about this camera :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2015 13:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/sony-a7ii-facts-and-thoughts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/sony-a7ii-facts-and-thoughts/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Newborn Photoshoot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago I took some portraits of a little human named Amelie. This was my very first newborn photoshoot, so after a few chats with Amelie’s Mum about what she’d like, along with a little Pinterest research, we set a date to do the shoot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/baby-amelie-sleepy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The heat and multiple feeds made little Amelie very sleepy&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;The heat and multiple feeds made little Amelie very sleepy&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amelie was only 11 days old, tiny and very cute. Her mother Sarah had the heating in the house on blast so that she wouldn’t be cold as we lay her out on blankets to take her portrait (pro tip!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/baby-amelie-blanket.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Baby Amelie&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Eleven day old Amelie&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tried a few different setups, including placing her in a wicker basket, curled up beside a few of her favourite cuddly toys and the “infinity blanket”. The latter involved draping a large blanket over the sofa a pillow, held in place with a few clothes-pegs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/baby-amelie-diptych.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Baby Amelie&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Amelie in a wicker blanket and in the infinity blanket setup&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shoot was a little more challenging than what Pinterest would have you believe. During the two hour shoot we paused for a few feedings and clean-ups, but little Amelie was a pleasure to shoot and proved to be very photogenic. I was very happy I had the chance to take Amelie’s portraits and there’s no better feeling when a client tells you how happy they are with the photos! :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 14:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/first-newborn-photoshoot/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/first-newborn-photoshoot/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hybrid Conf, You Were Amazing</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I had the pleasure of attending &lt;a href=&quot;http://hybridconf.net&quot;&gt;Hybrid&lt;/a&gt;, a conference for both web designers and developers alike. After reading so many great things about the conference in previous years, I was delighted to be there representing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eyekiller.com/blog/article/attending-hybrid-conf-2015-in-dublin&quot;&gt;Eyekiller&lt;/a&gt;, and getting the opportunity to listen to a variety of inspiring talks, given by speakers from all over the globe. On the Wednesday evening before the conference kicked off, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/sineadotoole&quot;&gt;Sinead&lt;/a&gt; and I began our road trip to Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there was something I could take away from every talk given inside the auditorium at Dublin City University, there were a few that really stood out to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his talk “Going Deeper,” &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/fehler&quot;&gt;Chris Murphy&lt;/a&gt; described how we should cast our net wide and broaden our knowledge in a range of topics, and explore those which interest us most, allowing us to find the connections and become better creatives. I really like the idea of becoming the &lt;a href=&quot;http://chiefexecutive.net/ideo-ceo-tim-brown-t-shaped-stars-the-backbone-of-ideoae%E2%84%A2s-collaborative-culture/&quot;&gt;“T-shaped Person”&lt;/a&gt; that he described, and I think this would lead to more effective collaborating when working with my team at Eyekiller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/hybrid-conf-speakers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;I met so many awesome people at Hybrid&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I met so many awesome people at Hybrid&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was difficult not to leave Dublin feeling refreshed and inspired after the two days of talks inside The Helix. Many of the speakers shared their journeys of working on the web, or a product, or even a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/mrbingo/hate-mail-the-definitive-collection/description&quot;&gt;rap video&lt;/a&gt;, and kept the audience captivated, and often, in flood of tears from laughing so much. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/darngooood&quot;&gt;Meg Lewis’&lt;/a&gt; 5 minute pocket talk has encouraged me to make a positive impact around me using my creative skills while not expecting anything in return, while &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/scott_riley&quot;&gt;Scott Riley’s&lt;/a&gt; talk proved how lucky we are to be in a community that is so open to sharing knowledge and support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zachinglis&quot;&gt;Zach&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/teawithlemon&quot;&gt;Laura&lt;/a&gt; did a stellar job of putting Hybrid together, as there wasn’t only a super speaker lineup, but also great treats for attendees and fun events around the conference, including the 90’s themed bowling. Sinead and I may not have been the best bowlers there, but we did win prizes for the best dancing of the evening, ha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/hybrid-best-dancers.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sinead and I win Best Dancers at Hybrid&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Sinead and I won prizes for being the best dancers at the Hybrid Bowling night out!&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlight of the trip for me, was meeting so many of the wonderful people that I’ve admired (and followed daily on Twitter) for so long. The culture of the event was one of inclusion, friendliness and with it being in Dublin, a lot of good craic. I have such a huge appreciation for the hard work Zach and Laura put into organising this amazing event. I hope that I get the chance to cross paths with everyone again soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to see more of my pictures from the conference, check out my &lt;a href=&quot;https://melissakeizer.exposure.co/hybrid-conf&quot;&gt;Exposure photo story!&lt;/a&gt; :)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2015 14:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/hybrid-conf/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/hybrid-conf/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hey, Take My Card</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After attending some local events with my camera where a few people asked about my freelance photography services, I thought it would be wise to have some personal business cards I can give out at future events. So, late one night last week I set about designing my cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know Sketch isn’t exactly designed for print work, but I set up my artboards and gave it a go anyway. Keeping the design inline with my personal website, I kept the design fairly minimal and used Adelle Sans, set in my website’s primary colours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/personal-business-cards-sketch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Designing my business cards in Sketch&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Who says Sketch can’t be used for print work?&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was keen to use &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moo.com/uk/share/#nxfrbj&quot;&gt;Moo&lt;/a&gt; as their square business cards with unique backs were exactly what I was after. I uploaded my design as a PDF for the front-side, along with 12 different photographs for the back of each card. This way, I could carry about a mini portfolio of my work in my purse! After completing my order, my cards arrived a few days later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/business-cards-moo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Delightful touches from Moo&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Delightful touches like these can really make a brand&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon opening the package a little blue card fell out, telling me I have cool hair, putting a smile on my face.  I then found my business cards inside a little black box.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/business-cards-portfolio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My new business cards&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A mini portfolio in my pocket&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very happy with the quality of the cards, the matte finish on their original paper was perfect. Moo served up a great user experience, from making the design and upload process on their website very easy, to providing simple delights when you receive the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’d definitely recommend you try them if you’re interested in having business cards made yourself. Oh and if you were to use my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.moo.com/uk/share/#nxfrbj&quot;&gt;referral code&lt;/a&gt; that would great ;)&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 14:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/hey-take-my-card/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/hey-take-my-card/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started with Git</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I gave a talk at local developer meetup &lt;a href=&quot;http://belfastruby.com/2014/01/30/intro-to-ruby.html&quot;&gt;Belfast Ruby&lt;/a&gt; on how get started with Git and GitHub. These are the notes that accompany the practical demo I gave, you can also check out my short Keynote on &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/melissakeizer/gitn-started-with-version-control&quot;&gt;Speakerdeck&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully this guide will still be useful to version control newbies now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-remote-repo&quot;&gt;1. Creating Remote Repo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create account/Sign in to Github.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create New Repo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give the project a name and description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have an online space for your project to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up-git&quot;&gt;2. Setting Up Git&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we’re going to open Terminal/iTerm and type some commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, check is Installed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git --version
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should get a response that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git version 1.8.3.1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already have Git installed or need to update (use version 1.7.11 or higher) then follow these links to install Git in your machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install [Git for Mac] (https://code.google.com/p/git-osx-installer/) or [Git for Windows] (http://msysgit.github.io/)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next give Git your credentials&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git config --global user.name &quot;Melissa Keizer&quot;
git config --global user.email &quot;mkeizer@rumblelabs.com&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-your-local-repo&quot;&gt;3. Create Your Local Repo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you need to make the repository for your project that will live on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terminal navigate to the folder where you keep your projects and make a new directory for your new app/site/project. Then navigate to your new project folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd sites
mkdir nice-project
cd nice-project
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to start using Git commands (They always begin with the word Git)
First you need to tell your computer to recognise this directory as a local Git Repository&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now you have both a remote and local git repo for your project.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-some-files&quot;&gt;4. Make Some Files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add a ReadMe.md file (Use this markdown file to add notes about your project and instructions about how others can get it running locally)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;touch ReadMe.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’ll edit this ReadMe file by opening it in my text editor of choice, Sublime Text 2. I’ve installed the Sublime Command Line tool which allows me to open my project from the command line - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/docs/2/osx_command_line.html&quot;&gt;Here’s how to set it up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;subl .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the ReadMe.md I added some markdown using Sublime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#Nice Project
This is my new nice project, holla.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check that Git can see your changes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git status
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The response tells me that Git notices the edit but the file is currently untracked. Next you need to tell Git to add in these changes so you can commit them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following this, commit the change. By commiting you are taking a snapshot of your project repo at this point in time. Remember to give your commits a meaningful description about what you just did&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add .
git commit -m &quot;Added a readme.md file and wrote some words in it&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next it’s time to push your changes to your remote repo on Github.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;connect-local-and-remote-repos&quot;&gt;5. Connect local and remote repos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to push these changes, I need to tell Git that a remote repo exists somewhere on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to Github and grab the link your project’s quick set up page. Remember to take the &lt;strong&gt;SSH link&lt;/strong&gt; if you have SSH keys set up (You can also use the HTTP link but this causes you to give your username and password everytime you push)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go back to terminal and type the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add origin git@github.com:melissakeizer/nice-project.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word “origin” indicates that this is a new place where files originate and “remote” simply tells git that the origin is with an online host  .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check that it was set up correctly type the command below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote -v
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see a list of all remote origins. I see it listed twice since Git will both push changes there and fetch changes from there. &lt;strong&gt;Now Git knows where you want your local changes to your repository to go!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push your changes use the command below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push -u origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at your changes by visiting the project page on Github. There I’ll see the updated ReadMe.md and I can click on the “Commits” link to view exactly what changes were made with each commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-a-new-branch&quot;&gt;6. Make a new branch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in my talk, branches are useful when working in teams or for simply separating development of different features on your app or project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a new branch type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git checkout -b branch-name
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “-b” indicates that this is a new branch. Give your branch a relevant name, for example “contact-form” or “new-design”
You can start making changes to your project without affecting your master branch, the main line of development. I made some edits to my ReadMe.md file in Sublime, then added and committed this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add .
git commit -m &quot;updated readme&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I’ll push this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll see a message in Terminal telling you that the branch has no upstream branch, to push the branch simply use the command listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push --set-upstream origin branch-name
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to merge in the changes you made on your branch later you must move to your master branch and give the merge command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git checkout master
git merge branch-name
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there’s a few Git fundamentals nailed down. Hopefully this will help you get started with Git on your own projects, but if you have any questions or run into issues feel free to tweet me &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/keizgoesboom&quot;&gt;@KeizGoesBoom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 23:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/getting-started-with-git/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/getting-started-with-git/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strobist Photography for Sony Alpha shooters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I’m out taking photos, I generally shoot the scene using the natural light outdoors, or the available light indoors, whether that’s stage lighting at a gig, or artificial light inside a room.  However there have been times when I’ve been shooting indoors in low-light and I’ve been forced to hike up my camera’s ISO setting, resulting in noisier (grainy) images. In those situations, I would have benefitted from having an off-camera flash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became more and more interested in strobist photography (i.e. using off-camera flashes, a.k.a. speedlights, to light a scene) so when asked for Christmas gift ideas last year, I decided to put some lighting equipment on my list.  It was a frustrating experience searching for answers regarding off-camera flash setups for Sony Alpha users, as there seems to be a lack of information available about this. Hopefully this post will be helpful in guiding other off-camera, wireless flash photography newbies, and in particular, fellow Sony Alpha shooters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/strobist-setup-sony-alpha.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Strobist setup for Sony Alpha&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I&#39;ll be detailing my strobist setup for Sony Alpha&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heres-what-youll-need&quot;&gt;Here’s what you’ll need&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few core pieces of equipment you’ll need to get started, along with your DSLR and lens. For reference, I use a Sony A580.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flash unit (Mine’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Sony-HVL-F58AM-High-Power-Flash/dp/B001C5TQFM/ref=sr_1_15?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1430619754&amp;amp;sr=8-15&amp;amp;keywords=sony+flashgun&quot;&gt;Sony HVL-F58AM&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B006JODEGI/ref=wl_it_dp_o_pC_S_ttl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;colid=2WET56E3WOQR2&amp;amp;coliid=I1NMYOL33CJUBE&quot;&gt;Trigger set&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0011363NS/ref=wl_it_dp_o_pC_nS_ttl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;colid=2WET56E3WOQR2&amp;amp;coliid=I3O1DQ66CL969B&quot;&gt;Light stand&lt;/a&gt; (if you’re likely to shoot outside you might want to buy a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/TARION-Studio-Counterbalance-Sandbag-Outdoor/dp/B00MYYBR5W/ref=sr_1_2?s=electronics&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1418741273&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=sandbag&quot;&gt;sandbag&lt;/a&gt; to weigh the stand down and stop it blowing over)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00EVL1K3K?psc=1&amp;amp;redirect=true&amp;amp;ref_=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00&quot;&gt;Umbrella mount/bracket&lt;/a&gt; for light stand (allows you to attach umbrella to light stand)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B001OKBLEE/ref=wl_it_dp_o_pC_nS_ttl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;colid=2WET56E3WOQR2&amp;amp;coliid=I2RQXS7N0NHJHG&quot;&gt;Shoot-through umbrella&lt;/a&gt; (before buying, check your holder’s maximum diameter is large enough to fit your umbrella’s shaft)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that my setup is for one flash only, if you want to use two speedlights, you’ll need another receiver for the flashgun, along with an extra stand, umbrella mount and umbrella. Another point to note is that most light stand holders use a cold-shoe mount to attach receivers and flashguns to the holder. However, Sony Alpha hotshoes are not the standard shape that most brands use, so instead you’ll need to order a holder with a screw top mount instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/strobist-phottix-strato.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My Phottix Strato II Wireless Trigger Set&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My Phottix Strato II Wireless Trigger Set&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading various online reviews and comments from Sony users on photography forums, I chose to add the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B006JODEGI/ref=wl_it_dp_o_pC_S_ttl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;colid=2WET56E3WOQR2&amp;amp;coliid=I1NMYOL33CJUBE&quot;&gt;Phottix Strato II trigger set&lt;/a&gt; to my equipment list as it seemed to be best quality, cost-effective option. While you could buy cheaper YungNuo triggers/receivers, there’s limited compatibility with Sony products and there’s a likelihood that they won’t work with older or future Sony flashes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-to-get-set-up&quot;&gt;Now to get set up!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by mounting the transmitter to your DSLR’s hotshoe. You’ll need to alter some settings on your camera so it knows that you’ll be using an off-camera flash. I can access these settings via the function menu (Fn button on the back) on my camera, going to the flash mode settings and changing the mode to wireless (WL). Don’t forget to change your white balance setting to “flash” while before you start taking photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you’ll need to take your light stand out of the bag, pull out the legs and set it up. Grab your umbrella holder and screw it on to the top of your light stand. To attach the Phottix receiver to the umbrella holder, simply screw it on. Attach the flash to the receiver by slipping it into the hotshoe. Open the umbrella and pop the shaft into the hole in the flash holder, tightening it using the screw on the holder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/strobist-flashgun.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My flashgun with transmitter attached, mounted on my light stand&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My flashgun with transmitter attached, mounted on my light stand&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that everything is in place, you’ll just need to turn on your flash, transmitter and receiver and fiddle about with a few more settings. Press on a channel button on your transmitter, when you see it light up, that’s it set. Turn on the same channel on your receiver. The Phottix Strato II trigger set doesn’t support wireless TTL (though you can use TTL when the flash is mounted on your transmitter on the camera.), so you’ll need to set the flash power manually. Of course, this depends on your scene and the results you’re after. Have a play about with the flashgun settings until your exposure is just right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a few photos and make sure the flash is firing. If you find the flash isn’t firing, check that both the transmitter and receiver are switched on and are using the same channel (the selected one will be lit up). Also check that the camera’s flash mode is set to “wireless.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;putting-my-strobist-setup-to-the-test&quot;&gt;Putting my strobist setup to the test&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently did a freelance photography job for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/thevaultbanbridge&quot;&gt;The Vault&lt;/a&gt;, a new restaurant in Banbridge, where I had chance to use my new lighting gear in a real-world situation. I had a mix of lighting available to work with at the pizzeria- from the dim, atmospheric lighting in the dining area to the wood-fired oven where the pizza was illuminated solely the flames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/strobist-pizza.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pizza in the Wood-fired Oven&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I lit this scene with a single flashgun, shot through an umbrella.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shoot involved plenty of experimentation to find the best way to light the scene, including the flash power settings and the position and distance of the stand from the scene. Sometimes the light from my flash was the primary light source for a shot, and other times it was used to add a little extra light to brighten up the scene a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/strobist-pizza-cutting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Pizza at The Vault&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I lit this scene with a single speedlight, shot through an umbrella.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comparing-with-and-without-flash&quot;&gt;Comparing with and without flash&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit of having a strobist setup is clear when comparing the shots below, taken one after another. The left photo shows the drinks lit with only the lights at the bar, the right photo shows the same scene lit by the flash. The left one is noticeably nosier as I had no choice but to bump up the ISO to compensate for a lack of available light. The right one is a much sharper shot with a lot less noise as I could reduce the ISO to 200.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;article__image article__image--with-caption&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/strobist-cocktails-comparison.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cocktails at The Vault&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A comparison of the same scene with (right) and without (left) flash.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-notes&quot;&gt;Final notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’d still consider myself a newbie when it comes to strobist photography, I learned a lot during the two photoshoots at the restaurant and being able to experiment with different settings. I found the one-flashgun setup to suit my needs perfectly in this case, but I may invest in another flash (and stand, umbrella bracket and light diffuser) in the future, especially since I hope to learn more about using speedlights for portraiture photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s definitely useful to have off-camera flash as you can’t always depend on available light to be enough. The great thing about strobist photography is that it’s cheaper than buying studio lighting and it’s also very portable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this post has helped clarify what you’ll need and how to get started. Post a comment if you have any questions! Oh and if you’re interested in seeing a few more photos from the shoot, take a look on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/tinyspark_boom/sets/72157652372228675/&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 02:50:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/strobist-photography-for-sony-alpha-shooters/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/strobist-photography-for-sony-alpha-shooters/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
