<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Melissa Keizer | Personal Website</title>
    <description>The portfolio and blog of Melissa Keizer - a UI/UX designer, front-end developer and photographer from Bangor, Northern Ireland.
</description>
    <link>http://melissakeizer.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://melissakeizer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 13:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 13:27:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ship it</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s well known that many designers struggle on settling on ideas and designs for their own portfolio sites, and sadly, I fell into that stereotype. For months, I’ve been creating various designs in Sketch that never quite made it to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became impatient, as my aim wasn’t to have a pixel-perfect website that showcased my latest work, but instead to act as a little corner of the internet where I can share my thoughts with the world. Finally I decided to embrace the motto, “just ship it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I just needed to build something, get it out there, and iterate over time, and this is exactly what I’m doing. So, today marks the &lt;em&gt;soft launch&lt;/em&gt; of my new website on the internet, but by no means is it finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a long list of to-dos on my Trello board, including layouts that need better considered, ideas for improving the reading experience of blog posts and some simple tweaks that would simply better the overall experience of using my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../img/blog/trello-to-dos.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;Trello&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My ever-growing to-do list on Trello&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing my site is now out and open to scrutiny motivates me to improve it, and I look forward to moving Trello tasks into the “done” list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I’m excited about writing again and sharing my thoughts in my journal. I’ve added comment functionality to my posts so I encourage you to share your opinions too and keep the conversation going.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/ship-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/ship-it.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
