<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Melissa Keizer | Personal Website</title>
    <description>The portfolio and blog of Melissa Keizer - a UI/UX designer, front-end developer and photographer from Bangor, Northern Ireland.
</description>
    <link>http://melissakeizer.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://melissakeizer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 07:49:28 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2015 07:49:28 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started with Git</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Last year I gave a talk at local developer meetup &lt;a href=&quot;http://belfastruby.com/2014/01/30/intro-to-ruby.html&quot;&gt;Belfast Ruby&lt;/a&gt; on how get started with Git and GitHub. These are the notes that accompany the practical demo I gave, you can also check out my short Keynote on &lt;a href=&quot;https://speakerdeck.com/melissakeizer/gitn-started-with-version-control&quot;&gt;Speakerdeck&lt;/a&gt;. Hopefully this guide will still be useful to version control newbies now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;creating-remote-repo&quot;&gt;1. Creating Remote Repo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create account/Sign in to Github.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create New Repo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Give the project a name and description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have an online space for your project to live.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up-git&quot;&gt;2. Setting Up Git&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we’re going to open Terminal/iTerm and type some commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, check is Installed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git --version
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should get a response that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git version 1.8.3.1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t already have Git installed or need to update (use version 1.7.11 or higher) then follow these links to install Git in your machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install [Git for Mac] (https://code.google.com/p/git-osx-installer/) or [Git for Windows] (http://msysgit.github.io/)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next give Git your credentials&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git config --global user.name &quot;Melissa Keizer&quot;
git config --global user.email &quot;mkeizer@rumblelabs.com&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;create-your-local-repo&quot;&gt;3. Create Your Local Repo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you need to make the repository for your project that will live on your computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terminal navigate to the folder where you keep your projects and make a new directory for your new app/site/project. Then navigate to your new project folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd sites
mkdir nice-project
cd nice-project
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now to start using Git commands (They always begin with the word Git)
First you need to tell your computer to recognise this directory as a local Git Repository&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git init
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now you have both a remote and local git repo for your project.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-some-files&quot;&gt;4. Make Some Files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add a ReadMe.md file (Use this markdown file to add notes about your project and instructions about how others can get it running locally)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;touch ReadMe.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I’ll edit this ReadMe file by opening it in my text editor of choice, Sublime Text 2. I’ve installed the Sublime Command Line tool which allows me to open my project from the command line - &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sublimetext.com/docs/2/osx_command_line.html&quot;&gt;Here’s how to set it up&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;subl .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the ReadMe.md I added some markdown using Sublime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;#Nice Project
This is my new nice project, holla.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check that Git can see your changes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git status
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The response tells me that Git notices the edit but the file is currently untracked. Next you need to tell Git to add in these changes so you can commit them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following this, commit the change. By commiting you are taking a snapshot of your project repo at this point in time. Remember to give your commits a meaningful description about what you just did&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add .
git commit -m &quot;Added a readme.md file and wrote some words in it&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next it’s time to push your changes to your remote repo on Github.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;connect-local-and-remote-repos&quot;&gt;5. Connect local and remote repos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to push these changes, I need to tell Git that a remote repo exists somewhere on the web.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to Github and grab the link your project’s quick set up page. Remember to take the &lt;strong&gt;SSH link&lt;/strong&gt; if you have SSH keys set up (You can also use the HTTP link but this causes you to give your username and password everytime you push)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go back to terminal and type the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote add origin git@github.com:melissakeizer/nice-project.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word “origin” indicates that this is a new place where files originate and “remote” simply tells git that the origin is with an online host  .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To check that it was set up correctly type the command below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git remote -v
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should see a list of all remote origins. I see it listed twice since Git will both push changes there and fetch changes from there. &lt;strong&gt;Now Git knows where you want your local changes to your repository to go!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To push your changes use the command below&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push -u origin master
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Look at your changes by visiting the project page on Github. There I’ll see the updated ReadMe.md and I can click on the “Commits” link to view exactly what changes were made with each commit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-a-new-branch&quot;&gt;6. Make a new branch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in my talk, branches are useful when working in teams or for simply separating development of different features on your app or project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make a new branch type:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git checkout -b branch-name
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “-b” indicates that this is a new branch. Give your branch a relevant name, for example “contact-form” or “new-design”
You can start making changes to your project without affecting your master branch, the main line of development. I made some edits to my ReadMe.md file in Sublime, then added and committed this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add .
git commit -m &quot;updated readme&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I’ll push this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll see a message in Terminal telling you that the branch has no upstream branch, to push the branch simply use the command listed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git push --set-upstream origin branch-name
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you want to merge in the changes you made on your branch later you must move to your master branch and give the merge command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git checkout master
git merge branch-name
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, there’s a few Git fundamentals nailed down. Hopefully this will help you get started with Git on your own projects, but if you have any questions or run into issues feel free to tweet me &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/keizgoesboom&quot;&gt;@KeizGoesBoom&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 23:01:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/getting-started-with-git/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/getting-started-with-git/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Strobist Photography for Sony Alpha shooters</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I’m out taking photos, I generally shoot the scene using the natural light outdoors, or the available light indoors, whether that’s stage lighting at a gig, or artificial light inside a room.  However there have been times when I’ve been shooting indoors in low-light and I’ve been forced to hike up my camera’s ISO setting, resulting in noisier (grainy) images. In those situations, I would have benefitted from having an off-camera flash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became more and more interested in strobist photography (i.e. using off-camera flashes, a.k.a. speedlights, to light a scene) so when asked for Christmas gift ideas last year, I decided to put some lighting equipment on my list.  It was a frustrating experience searching for answers regarding off-camera flash setups for Sony Alpha users, as there seems to be a lack of information available about this. Hopefully this post will be helpful in guiding other off-camera, wireless flash photography newbies, and in particular, fellow Sony Alpha shooters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/strobist-setup-sony-alpha.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;Strobist setup for Sony Alpha&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I’ll be detailing my strobist setup for Sony Alpha&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heres-what-youll-need&quot;&gt;Here’s what you’ll need&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few core pieces of equipment you’ll need to get started, along with your DSLR and lens. For reference, I use a Sony A580.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flash unit (Mine’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/Sony-HVL-F58AM-High-Power-Flash/dp/B001C5TQFM/ref=sr_1_15?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1430619754&amp;amp;sr=8-15&amp;amp;keywords=sony+flashgun&quot;&gt;Sony HVL-F58AM&lt;/a&gt; )&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B006JODEGI/ref=wl_it_dp_o_pC_S_ttl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;colid=2WET56E3WOQR2&amp;amp;coliid=I1NMYOL33CJUBE&quot;&gt;Trigger set&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B0011363NS/ref=wl_it_dp_o_pC_nS_ttl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;colid=2WET56E3WOQR2&amp;amp;coliid=I3O1DQ66CL969B&quot;&gt;Light stand&lt;/a&gt; (if you’re likely to shoot outside you might want to buy a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/TARION-Studio-Counterbalance-Sandbag-Outdoor/dp/B00MYYBR5W/ref=sr_1_2?s=electronics&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1418741273&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=sandbag&quot;&gt;sandbag&lt;/a&gt; to weigh the stand down and stop it blowing over)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00EVL1K3K?psc=1&amp;amp;redirect=true&amp;amp;ref_=oh_aui_detailpage_o00_s00&quot;&gt;Umbrella mount/bracket&lt;/a&gt; for light stand (allows you to attach umbrella to light stand)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B001OKBLEE/ref=wl_it_dp_o_pC_nS_ttl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;colid=2WET56E3WOQR2&amp;amp;coliid=I2RQXS7N0NHJHG&quot;&gt;Shoot-through umbrella&lt;/a&gt; (before buying, check your holder’s maximum diameter is large enough to fit your umbrella’s shaft)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that my setup is for one flash only, if you want to use two speedlights, you’ll need another receiver for the flashgun, along with an extra stand, umbrella mount and umbrella. Another point to note is that most light stand holders use a cold-shoe mount to attach receivers and flashguns to the holder. However, Sony Alpha hotshoes are not the standard shape that most brands use, so instead you’ll need to order a holder with a screw top mount instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/strobist-phottix-strato.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;My Phottix Strato II Wireless Trigger Set&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My Phottix Strato II Wireless Trigger Set&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading various online reviews and comments from Sony users on photography forums, I chose to add the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.co.uk/dp/B006JODEGI/ref=wl_it_dp_o_pC_S_ttl?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;colid=2WET56E3WOQR2&amp;amp;coliid=I1NMYOL33CJUBE&quot;&gt;Phottix Strato II trigger set&lt;/a&gt; to my equipment list as it seemed to be best quality, cost-effective option. While you could buy cheaper YungNuo triggers/receivers, there’s limited compatibility with Sony products and there’s a likelihood that they won’t work with older or future Sony flashes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-to-get-set-up&quot;&gt;Now to get set up!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by mounting the transmitter to your DSLR’s hotshoe. You’ll need to alter some settings on your camera so it knows that you’ll be using an off-camera flash. I can access these settings via the function menu (Fn button on the back) on my camera, going to the flash mode settings and changing the mode to wireless (WL). Don’t forget to change your white balance setting to “flash” while before you start taking photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next you’ll need to take your light stand out of the bag, pull out the legs and set it up. Grab your umbrella holder and screw it on to the top of your light stand. To attach the Phottix receiver to the umbrella holder, simply screw it on. Attach the flash to the receiver by slipping it into the hotshoe. Open the umbrella and pop the shaft into the hole in the flash holder, tightening it using the screw on the holder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/strobist-flashgun.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;My flashgun with transmitter attached, mounted on my light stand&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My flashgun with transmitter attached, mounted on my light stand&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that everything is in place, you’ll just need to turn on your flash, transmitter and receiver and fiddle about with a few more settings. Press on a channel button on your transmitter, when you see it light up, that’s it set. Turn on the same channel on your receiver. The Phottix Strato II trigger set doesn’t support wireless TTL (though you can use TTL when the flash is mounted on your transmitter on the camera.), so you’ll need to set the flash power manually. Of course, this depends on your scene and the results you’re after. Have a play about with the flashgun settings until your exposure is just right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a few photos and make sure the flash is firing. If you find the flash isn’t firing, check that both the transmitter and receiver are switched on and are using the same channel (the selected one will be lit up). Also check that the camera’s flash mode is set to “wireless.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;putting-my-strobist-setup-to-the-test&quot;&gt;Putting my strobist setup to the test&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently did a freelance photography job for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/thevaultbanbridge&quot;&gt;The Vault&lt;/a&gt;, a new restaurant in Banbridge, where I had chance to use my new lighting gear in a real-world situation. I had a mix of lighting available to work with at the pizzeria- from the dim, atmospheric lighting in the dining area to the wood-fired oven where the pizza was illuminated solely the flames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/strobist-pizza.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;Pizza in the Wood-fired Oven&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I lit this scene with a single flashgun, shot through an umbrella.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shoot involved plenty of experimentation to find the best way to light the scene, including the flash power settings and the position and distance of the stand from the scene. Sometimes the light from my flash was the primary light source for a shot, and other times it was used to add a little extra light to brighten up the scene a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/strobist-pizza-cutting.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;Pizza at The Vault&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I lit this scene with a single speedlight, shot through an umbrella.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comparing-with-and-without-flash&quot;&gt;Comparing with and without flash&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefit of having a strobist setup is clear when comparing the shots below, taken one after another. The left photo shows the drinks lit with only the lights at the bar, the right photo shows the same scene lit by the flash. The left one is noticeably nosier as I had no choice but to bump up the ISO to compensate for a lack of available light. The right one is a much sharper shot with a lot less noise as I could reduce the ISO to 200.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/strobist-cocktails-comparison.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;Cocktails at The Vault&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A comparison of the same scene with (right) and without (left) flash. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-notes&quot;&gt;Final notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’d still consider myself a newbie when it comes to strobist photography, I learned a lot during the two photoshoots at the restaurant and being able to experiment with different settings. I found the one-flashgun setup to suit my needs perfectly in this case, but I may invest in another flash (and stand, umbrella bracket and light diffuser) in the future, especially since I hope to learn more about using speedlights for portraiture photography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s definitely useful to have off-camera flash as you can’t always depend on available light to be enough. The great thing about strobist photography is that it’s cheaper than buying studio lighting and it’s also very portable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this post has helped clarify what you’ll need and how to get started. Post a comment if you have any questions! Oh and if you’re interested in seeing a few more photos from the shoot, take a look on my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/photos/tinyspark_boom/sets/72157652372228675/&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2015 02:50:42 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/strobist-photography-for-sony-alpha-shooters/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/strobist-photography-for-sony-alpha-shooters/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tot Ziens, Rumble Labs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is my last day as a Rumbler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a year and nine months of working with the amazing team at &lt;a href=&quot;http://rumblelabs.com&quot;&gt;Rumble Labs&lt;/a&gt;, I am moving on to pastures new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined the team after completing my degree in Interactive Multimedia Design, starting work two days before my graduation in July 2013. Being Rumble’s first (and still only) female hire, I earned the affectionate nickname “Number One Girl in Rumble.” Thanks, &lt;a href=&quot;http://rumblelabs.com/about/steven-hylands/&quot;&gt;Steven!&lt;/a&gt; ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumble’s open and collaborative culture was the perfect place for me to grow as a designer and developer, as it encouraged knowledge sharing, pair programming and generally just helping teammates when you can. When &lt;a href=&quot;http://rumblelabs.com/about/mark-leetch/&quot;&gt;Mark&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; I weren’t exchanging &lt;a href=&quot;http://gfycat.com/SplendidSimpleHackee&quot;&gt;Nicki Minaj gifs&lt;/a&gt;, we’d often be found sat side-by-side, working together on a project. This helped us work out problems more efficiently, and I usually picked up a nifty development trick while I was there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/rumble-lads-selfie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;The Rumble Lads&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I’m going to miss the Rumble Lads!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My education at Rumble wasn’t limited to design and code. Luckily I had &lt;a href=&quot;http://rumblelabs.com/about/simon-hamilton/&quot;&gt;Simon&lt;/a&gt; there to teach me the art of &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/cOrrG0i1Rq/&quot;&gt;wine swirling&lt;/a&gt;, and with countless matches during the annual Rumbledon Tournament, I went from terrible to mediocre at playing table tennis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friendships with the Rumble lads extend outside of the office, as we’ve made some brilliant memories during various work events, Design Department &lt;a href=&quot;https://melissakeizer.exposure.co/designers-explorers&quot;&gt;photography trips&lt;/a&gt; and during the Rumble London trip last year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/design-dept-photography-trip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;Design Department Photography trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A Design Department photography day out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so happy to have been part of such a super team and having the opportunity to work on plenty of interesting client and internal projects, and share an office (and a Hipchat room) with such talented and hilarious people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So thank you for everything Rumble! I’ll really miss working with you guys, though I know we’ll still be getting together for regular catch ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-now&quot;&gt;So, what now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m deighted to announce that next week I’ll be starting my new job with the awesome team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eyekiller.com/&quot;&gt;Eyekiller&lt;/a&gt;. I’m very excited to dive into my UX and design role and get to know my new colleagues, and hopefully make some more great friends!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/tot-ziens-rumble-labs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/tot-ziens-rumble-labs/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ship it</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s well known that many designers struggle on settling on ideas and designs for their own portfolio sites, and sadly, I fell into that stereotype. For months, I’ve been creating various designs in Sketch that never quite made it to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became impatient, as my aim wasn’t to have a pixel-perfect website that showcased my latest work, but instead to act as a little corner of the internet where I can share my thoughts with the world. Finally I decided to embrace the motto, “just ship it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I just needed to build something, get it out there, and iterate over time, and this is exactly what I’m doing. So, today marks the &lt;em&gt;soft launch&lt;/em&gt; of my new website on the internet, but by no means is it finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a long list of to-dos on my Trello board, including layouts that need better considered, ideas for improving the reading experience of blog posts and some simple tweaks that would simply better the overall experience of using my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/trello-to-dos.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;Trello&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My ever-growing to-do list on Trello&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing my site is now out and open to scrutiny motivates me to improve it, and I look forward to moving Trello tasks into the “done” list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I’m excited about writing again and sharing my thoughts in my journal. I’ve added comment functionality to my posts so I encourage you to share your opinions too and keep the conversation going.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/ship-it/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/ship-it/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
