<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Melissa Keizer | Personal Website</title>
    <description>The portfolio and blog of Melissa Keizer - a UI/UX designer, front-end developer and photographer from Bangor, Northern Ireland.
</description>
    <link>http://melissakeizer.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://melissakeizer.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 22:01:21 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 22:01:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tot Ziens, Rumble Labs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is my last day as a Rumbler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a year and nine months of working with the amazing team at &lt;a href=&quot;http://rumblelabs.com&quot;&gt;Rumble Labs&lt;/a&gt;, I am moving on to pastures new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined the team after completing my degree in Interactive Multimedia Design, starting work two days before my graduation in July 2013. Being Rumble’s first (and still only) female hire, I earned the affectionate nickname “Number One Girl in Rumble.” Thanks, &lt;a href=&quot;http://rumblelabs.com/about/steven-hylands/&quot;&gt;Steven!&lt;/a&gt; ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rumble’s open and collaborative culture was the perfect place for me to grow as a designer and developer, as it encouraged knowledge sharing, pair programming and generally just helping teammates when you can. When &lt;a href=&quot;http://rumblelabs.com/about/mark-leetch/&quot;&gt;Mark&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; I weren’t exchanging &lt;a href=&quot;http://gfycat.com/SplendidSimpleHackee&quot;&gt;Nicki Minaj gifs&lt;/a&gt;, we’d often be found sat side-by-side, working together on a project. This helped us work out problems more efficiently, and I usually picked up a nifty development trick while I was there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/rumble-lads-selfie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;The Rumble Lads&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;I’m going to miss the Rumble Lads!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My education at Rumble wasn’t limited to design and code. Luckily I had &lt;a href=&quot;http://rumblelabs.com/about/simon-hamilton/&quot;&gt;Simon&lt;/a&gt; there to teach me the art of &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/p/cOrrG0i1Rq/&quot;&gt;wine swirling&lt;/a&gt;, and with countless matches during the annual Rumbledon Tournament, I went from terrible to mediocre at playing table tennis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friendships with the Rumble lads extend outside of the office, as we’ve made some brilliant memories during various work events, Design Department &lt;a href=&quot;https://melissakeizer.exposure.co/designers-explorers&quot;&gt;photography trips&lt;/a&gt; and during the Rumble London trip last year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/design-dept-photography-trip.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;Design Department Photography trip&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;A Design Department photography day out&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m so happy to have been part of such a super team and having the opportunity to work on plenty of interesting client and internal projects, and share an office (and a Hipchat room) with such talented and hilarious people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So thank you for everything Rumble! I’ll really miss working with you guys, though I know we’ll still be getting together for regular catch ups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-now&quot;&gt;So, what now?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m deighted to announce that next week I’ll be starting my new job with the awesome team at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eyekiller.com/&quot;&gt;Eyekiller&lt;/a&gt;. I’m very excited to dive into my UX and design role and get to know my new colleagues, and hopefully make some more great friends!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/tot-ziens-rumble-labs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/tot-ziens-rumble-labs/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ship it</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s well known that many designers struggle on settling on ideas and designs for their own portfolio sites, and sadly, I fell into that stereotype. For months, I’ve been creating various designs in Sketch that never quite made it to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became impatient, as my aim wasn’t to have a pixel-perfect website that showcased my latest work, but instead to act as a little corner of the internet where I can share my thoughts with the world. Finally I decided to embrace the motto, “just ship it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided that I just needed to build something, get it out there, and iterate over time, and this is exactly what I’m doing. So, today marks the &lt;em&gt;soft launch&lt;/em&gt; of my new website on the internet, but by no means is it finished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a long list of to-dos on my Trello board, including layouts that need better considered, ideas for improving the reading experience of blog posts and some simple tweaks that would simply better the overall experience of using my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../../img/blog/trello-to-dos.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;photo caption&quot; title=&quot;Trello&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;My ever-growing to-do list on Trello&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing my site is now out and open to scrutiny motivates me to improve it, and I look forward to moving Trello tasks into the “done” list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I’m excited about writing again and sharing my thoughts in my journal. I’ve added comment functionality to my posts so I encourage you to share your opinions too and keep the conversation going.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2015 11:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://melissakeizer.com/journal/ship-it/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://melissakeizer.com/journal/ship-it/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
